J. Robert Oppenheimer Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speech, Lecture, and Writing File, 1926-1966 (Box 238-288)
  - General Writings, 1939-1966 (Box 241-288)
    - North American Newspaper Alliance, 1945
    - North Carolina, University of, Chapel Hill, N.C., 1959-1964, (3 folders)
    - Northwestern University, Evanston, Ill., 1955-1956, undated, (2 folders) (Box 269)
    - The Open Mind, 1954-1966, (10 folders)
    - Organization of American States visit, 1961-1962, undated, (9 folders) (Box 270)
    - Paix, Université de, Huy, Belgium, 1964-1965 (Box 271)
    - Pan American Union, 1961
    - Paris, University of, Paris, France, 1958-1964, (4 folders)
    - Partisan Review, 1962 (Box 272)
    - Parvin Foundation, 1962-1964, (4 folders)
    - Pathe News, 1949
    - Pennsylvania, University of, Philadelphia, Pa., 1946, 1954-1961, (3 folders)
    - Petersen, Aage, proposed publication re Niels Bohr, 1963
    - Phillips Academy, Andover, Mass., 1961
    - Phillips Exeter Academy, Exeter, N.H., 1955-1956, (4 folders)
    - Press and Union League Club, 1957 (Box 273)
    - Press special, Amerika, circa 1957
    - Princeton Borough Teachers Association, Princeton, N.J., 1960-1961
    - Princeton High School, Princeton, N.J., 1964
    - Princeton Old Guard, 1955
    - Princeton Theological Seminary, Princeton, N.J., 1958
    - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J.
      - 1946-1965, n.d, (9 folders)
      - 1959-1963, (8 folders) (Box 274)
    - Puerto Rico, University of, Rio Piedro, P.R., 1959-1960, (3 folders) (Box 275)
    - Pyramid Club Achievement Award, 1954
    - Queen's University, Kingston, Canada, 1959-1960, (2 folders)
    - Radiodiffusion--Télévision Française, 1958-1962, (2 folders)
    - Radiotelevisione Italiana, 1963-1964
    - Réalites, 1957, 1963, (3 folders)
    - Reed College, Portland, Oreg., 1959-1960
    - Reith Lectures, 1952-1967, (8 folders); (10 folders); (7 folders) (Box 276, Box 277, Box 278, Box 279)
    - Rencontres Internationales de Généve, 1964, (5 folders)
    - Reviews of Modern Physics, 1955-1956 (Box 280)
    - Rochester-Geneva Conference, 1957-1958, (2 folders)
    - Rochester Institute of International Affairs, 1948-1954, (6 folders)
    - Rochester, University of, Rochester, N.Y., 1955-1956
    - Rockefeller Institute, New York, N.Y., 1963-1964
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, NBC program, 1950, (2 folders)
    - Roosevelt University, Chicago, Ill., 1955-1961, (5 folders) (Box 281)
    - Rothschild Foundation, 1965-1966
    - Ruechardt, Edward, book, 1957
    - Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J., 1958
    - San Francisco Chronicle, 1946
    - Saturday Evening Post, 1957-1963, (4 folders)
    - Saturday Review, 1956-1966
    - Science, 1959 (Box 282)
    - Science Talent Search, 1949-1951, 1960, (5 folders)
    - Scientific American, 1950, (2 folders)
    - Seven Springs Farm, Mt. Kisco, N.Y., 1963
    - Sewanee Review, 1956-1958
    - Smith College, Northampton, Mass., 1948-1949 (Box 283)
    - Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., 1964-1966, (5 folders)
    - Société Française de Philosophic Conference, 1958-1960
    - Solvay Congress, 1948-1958, (3 folders) (Box 284)
    - Space Technology Laboratories, Los Angeles, Calif., 1959-1962
    - Stanford University, Stanford, Calif., 1960
    - State Department, 1950
    - Swarthmore College, Swarthmore, Pa., 1953-1959
    - Taylor, Harold, dinner for, 1959-1960
    - Teleradio, 1966
    - Tempo, 1963
    - Think, 1959-1962
    - This Week Magazine, 1955-1959
    - Tribune Libre Universitaire, 1961 (Box 285)
    - Truman, MIT talk, 1949
    - Tupper and Love, Inc., re chapter contributed by Oppenheimer to book titled Listen to Leaders in Science, 1964-1965
    - Twentieth anniversary of atomic bomb attack on Hiroshima, Japan, 1965
    - UNESCO, 1964-1966, (4 folders)
    - United Nations Atomic Energy Commission, 1946-1948, (2 folders)
    - U.S. Army, 1964-1965, (2 folders) (Box 286)
    - Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, N.Y., 1958
    - Von Neumann, John, 1957
    - Washington Post, 1965-1966, (3 folders)
    - Wayne State University, Detroit, Mich., 1957-1959
    - Weaver's symposium, 1959-1965, (2 folders) (Box 287)
    - Weisskopf, Victor F. (“Viki”), 1964-1966
    - Weizmann Institute of Science, Rehovoth, Israel, 1958-1962, (4 folders)
    - Westinghouse, 1946-1966, (3 folders)
    - Whidden Lecture See Container 265, McMaster University
    - Whose Is Atomic Power? 1954-1957 (Box 288)
    - Wisconsin, University of, Madison, Wisc., 1958-1959
    - World University Service, 1956
    - Yale University, New Haven, Conn., 1959
    - Yukawa, Hideki, 1949-1950
    - Unidentified, Undated
- Miscellany, 1957-1959 (Box 289-290)
  Printed matter, photographs, and an incomplete card index of Oppenheimer's memberships.
  - Partial index to memberships and invitations, 1957-1958 (Box 289)
  - Photographs, 1958, undated
  - Printed matter, 1959 (Box 290)
- Government File Supplement, 1941-1953 (Box 291-293)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, memoranda, manuscript and near-print research reports, and scientific photographs.
  - 1941-1946, (14 folders) (Box 291)
  - 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 292)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1949-1953, (5 folders) (Box 293)
- Addition I, 1921-1980 (Box 294)
  Originals and copies of letters sent. Arranged alphabetically by name of recipient. Also miscellaneous files containing printed and near-print matter, photographs, writings by others, and a microfilm copy of a history of the Institute for Advanced Study.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic, type of material, or title.
  - Correspondence (Box 294)
    - Bernheim, Frederick, 1945
    - Fergusson, Francis, 1923-1926
    - Horgan, Paul, 1923, 1964
    - Oppenheimer, Frank, 1926-1935
    - Oppenheimer, Lee W., 1945
    - Singer, Louise Oppenheimer, 1937-1939
    - Smith, Herbert W., 1922-1926, 1945-1948, 1954, (2 folders)
    - Uehling, Edwin A. and Ruth, 1934, 1940-1944, 1955
    - Uhlenbeck, George, 1927-1940
    - Unidentified, 1945
  - Miscellany
    - “A History of the Institute for Advanced Study, 1930-1950, ” by Beatrice M. Stern, microfilm copy, 1964, Microfilm shelf no. 16,646. Not available on interlibrary loan.
    - Judging poetry, 1921
    - Printed matter, near-print material, and photographs, 1948-1967
    - Writings by others, 1942-1965, (2 folders)
- Addition II, 1947-1957 (Box 295-301)
  Incoming correspondence received from the general public and inventories of classified documents.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Inventories of classified documents (Box 295)
    - Declassified material, 1953
    - Miscellaneous material, 1954-1955
    - Navy Department, 1955
    - Research and Development Board, 1954
    - State Department, 1954-1955
    - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1954-1955, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 296)
  - Correspondence
    - Anonymous, 1948-1955
    - Autograph requests, 1947-1955, (2 folders)
    - "A" miscellaneous, 1948-1954
    - "B-E" miscellaneous, 1948-1957, (7 folders) (Box 297)
    - "F-H" miscellaneous, 1947-1955, (7 folders) (Box 298)
    - "I-M" miscellaneous, 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 299)
    - "N-R" miscellaneous, 1948-1955, (6 folders) (Box 300)
    - "S-W" miscellaneous, 1947-1955, (8 folders) (Box 301)
- Classified, 1944-1954 (Box CL 1)
  Classified government documents consisting mostly of correspondence and reports.
  Organized and described according to the series, folders, and boxes from which the items were removed.
  - General Case File (Box CL 1)
    - Bohr, Niels
      - Writings, 1944 (Container 21) See Top Secret
    - Weil, George L.
      - Correspondence, 1948 (Container 77) See Restricted Data
  - Government File
    - State Department
      - Disarmament File
        - Articles on disarmanent, undated (Container 191)
  - Security Case File
    - Atomic Energy Commission case
      - Classified file, 1953 (Container 197)
    - Letters
      - Friends and special interest, 1954 (Container 202)
- Top Secret, 1944 (Box TS 1)
  Classified government documents consisting of memoranda and a report.
  - General Case File (Box TS 1)
    - Bohr, Niels
      - Writings, 1944
- Restricted Data, 1948 (Box RD 1)
  Restricted government documents consisting of correspondence.
  - General Case File (Box RD 1)
    - Weil, George L.
      - Correspondence, 1948